原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译     草草  累  joy_bwl  子V  马丁  米糊  陈奥奥
翻译     AliciaLee1990  小涵同学  碗沉  小酸奶
校对     草
时间轴     猹猹  大葱  DA
后期     拉图
总监     王小麦
你打过仗  对吗
You were in the war, weren't you?
你拿烟的手势
The way you hold your cigarette,
用手掌接烟灰
hiding the ember in your palm.
大概是还保持着
I guess I'm still trying not to give 'em
不要暴露踪迹的习惯
something to shoot at.
梅森探案集
前情提要
一起难以启齿的惨剧降临到他们头上
An unspeakable act was visited upon us.
天使铁路凶案
他们是你的朋友
Friends of yours?
我教堂的成员
Members of my church.
上帝广播集会
The Radiant Assembly of God.
有人潜入艾米莉家绑走了她的孩子
Someone creeps in Emily's house and nabs her kid?
所以你同意警方的观点
So you agree with the police.
你觉得多德森一家脱不了干系
You think the Dodson's had something to do with it.
我没同意任何人的观点
I'm not agreeing with anyone.
不管怎么看都很奇怪
It's queer from both sides.
我要拿下多德森
I'm gonna nail Dodson.
一定是发现你有问题
Gotta know something stinks around you.
你们为什么不报警
Why didn't you call the police?
我没有绑架我儿子
I didn't kidnap my son!
有人把眼皮缝起来了
Someone stitched those eyes.
是你见过最惨烈的情况
Worse thing you've ever seen.
这些都不在计划里
None of this was part of the plan.
我应该逃跑的
I should have run.
晚上好先生们  不好意思我来晚了
Evening gentlemen, sorry I'm late.
快点搞定吧
Let's get this over with.
现在有了这么个委托
This is a live one.
上刺刀
Fix bayonets!
上刺刀  快点  站好位置
Fix bayonets. Let's go. Watch your points.
快点  准备好
Come on, make ready.
-精神点  别死了  -是  长官
- Look alive, stay alive. - Yes, sir.
靠近  上前
Yeah. Close in, close in.
做好准备
Make ready.
Make ready!
准备好
Get ready.
冲啊
Edendale!
往前冲
Hit the line!
冲啊
Come on!
跟我来  小伙子们
Follow me, boys!
梅森探案集
第一季 第二集
-梅森  -新年快乐
- Mason. - Happy New Year.
你还说
Says you.
嗯  你想要线吗
Yeah. You wanted thread?
都在这里
There's thread.
我能想象上帝
And I can imagine God,
打开他的世界之书  暗自思量
opening up his book of the world and wondering to himself,
"今天谁最需要我"
"Who needs me most today?"
我能想象他的大手  翻着书页
And I can imagine his great hand flipping the pages
翻到我们的城市时  停了下来
and stopping when he comes to our city.
洛杉矶迎来了异教的早餐
It's a heathen's morning in Los Angeles!
从圣塔莫尼卡的赌博船
From the gambling boats off Santa Monica
到百老汇上的妓院
to the brothels on Broadway,
他们喝着酒
they are tipping back their bottles,
在小巷里媾和
rolling bones in the alley,
远离了皈依基督的生活
cheating themselves out of a life with Christ!
撒谎者
Liars!
小偷
Thieves!
通奸者
Fornicators!
那是魔鬼桌前的宾客
Guests at the Devil's table,
吃着七道菜的丰盛大餐  身体满足
served a seven-course meal, that feeds the body,
灵魂却饥饿
but starves the soul.
阿门
Amen!
是吧  妈妈
Isn't that right, Mother?
说得太对了  爱丽丝修女
It most certainly is, Sister Alice.
兄弟姐妹们
Brothers and Sisters,
我得到了使命
I've been given a calling,
我得到了声音  还有一对
been given a voice and gifted a set of lungs
能让泰山嫉妒的
that would make Tarzan himself
好肺
green with envy!
不不  我不是说你
No, no, no, no. I'm not talking about you.
你坐下吧
You sit your hindquarters back down.
我有使命和特权
It is my purpose and privilege
在这新年的第一天
on this very first day of the very new year...
我知道来这里并不容易
And I know it ain't been easy getting here.
我们都曾
Now, we have all known
经历过困难
our share of rough times.
我们都知道
We all know what it's like
饿着肚子睡觉的滋味
to go to bed with an empty stomach.
阿门
Amen!
但光芒会的兄弟姐妹们
But Brothers and Sisters of Radiant Light,
以及在家听广播的各位
and you listening at home on your radio boxes,
我此时此刻想告诉你们
I am here to tell you right here and right now,
你们还有一张桌子可以坐
there is another table where you can sit
品尝上帝烹饪的美食
with food from a kitchen where God does the cooking!
而桌上也有七道菜
And it, too, serves seven courses!
大家跟我一起喊
I shout it, you shout it!
-纯洁  -纯洁
- Chastity! - Chastity!
-节欲  -节欲
- Temperance! - Temperance!
-施舍  -施舍
- Charity! - Charity!
-勤奋  -勤奋
- Diligence! - Diligence!
-耐心  -耐心
- Patience! - Patience!
-感恩  -感恩
- Gratitude! - Gratitude!
-还有谦逊  -谦逊
- And humility! - Humility!
*长老们  咱们绕墙走*
*Come on elders Let's go around the wall*
*这称我的心意*
*That suits me*
*长老们  咱们绕墙走*
*Oh, come on elders Let's go around the wall*
*这称我的心意*
*That suits me*
她是不是一个奇迹
Oh, isn't she a wonder?
一座灯塔
A beacon?
我们罪人的滩头堡
A beachhead for us sinners?
如果可以  请大方一些
Oh, give generously if you can,
为周围的光芒献上一份爱
give gloriously for the radiance around you.
留心我们修女的劝导
Heed the words of our Sister,
在这个美妙的早晨
and dig as deep into your pockets
尽量慷慨解囊  乐善好施
as God will allow you on this great and good morning!
摒弃罪恶  接纳美德
Kick those sins out, and welcome those virtues in!
我想看到盘子高高叠起
I wanna see those plates piled so high,
我想看到桶满溢出
I want to see those buckets brimming.
他们来了吗
Oh, are they here?
是的  他们在等你
Ah, yes, they're waiting for you.
母亲非常脆弱
The mother is very fragile...
你太兴奋了
You overcooked yourself.
要我私下见他们吗
You want me to meet with them privately?
不  必须是现在
No, no, it has to be now.
我先喘口气
I just-- I have to catch my breath.
-我表现得好吗  -当然
- I was good out there? - Oh, you were.
仿若圣人  比肩摩西
Halfway to Heaven, a mile from Moses.
《圣经》故事中犹太人古代领袖
爱丽丝修女  这是马修和艾米莉·多德森
Sister Alice, this is Matthew and Emily Dodson.
我听说以后  每日每夜都在祈祷
I've been praying every night and every morning
艾米莉小姐
since I heard, Miss Emily.
谢谢你  修女
Thank you, Sister.
现在只能依靠上帝了
God is about all we have right now.
他与你同在
And He is with you.
来  坐下
Come on, sit down.
我们在家里待了快一周了
We've been in our home for nearly a week.
我想着还是
I thought it might be a good idea
带艾米莉回圣殿吧
to get Emily back here to the Temple.
然后我们收到了你让我们来后台的邀请
Then we received your invitation to come backstage.
我在报纸上看到你们的照片  我就对妈妈说
I saw your picture in the paper and I said to my mother,
"我们必须  必须  必须尽力帮助他们"
"We must, must, must do everything we can for them."
-是吧  妈妈  -一字不差  修女
- Didn't I say that, Mother? - The very words, Sister.
如果你还没安排好
If you haven't made arrangements,
我们希望能在圣殿为查理举办葬礼
we'd like to offer the Temple for Charlie's funeral.
长老们愿意支付一切费用
The Elders have offered to pay for any and all expenses.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢  巴格利先生
Thank you, Mr. Baggerly.
多德森先生和太太
Mr. And Mrs. Dodson.
-警探  -霍尔科姆
- Detective... - Holcomb.
不好意思  打扰了
Uh, excuse me for, uh... interrupting,
你们俩要跟我去一趟市里
I need both of you to come with me downtown.
什么情况
What's this?
是好消息  我们要给你们看一组嫌疑人
That's good news. We got a line-up to show you.
但我们现在就得走
But we need to go now.
只是跑跑腿  查查那辆车
It's just a little legwork. Do some digging on the car.
查查马修的不在场证明
Run down an alibi for Matthew.
酬劳很丰厚
There-- there's good money here.
上次六百块变成一块的时候你也是这么说的
You said that last time when 600 dollars turned into one.
我这是在补偿你
I'm-- I'm trying to make it up to you.
我说什么来着  不要瞄头
The hell did I say? Never aim at the head.
-我保证你会拿到钱的  -不要保证  先付钱
- I promise you, you'll get paid. - Don't promise. Pay.
你付钱吗  说啊  我还要养家糊口呢
Are you paying? Say you're paying 'cause I got mouths to feed.
EB付钱
E.B.'s paying.
EB觉得我是废物
E.B. E.B. thinks I'm a degenerate.
他还觉得你是个好调查员
And a good investigator. He also thinks that.
我需要一个教了我一半知识的人
I-- I need the guy who taught me half of what I know.
一半  是全部吧
Half? Try everything.
好吧  我这里有
All right. I have...
23块
twenty-three dollars.
先拿这钱垫上杂费  当是对丘比那事的补偿
You can pad the expenses as a sorry for the Chubby thing.
-露蒂  -干什么
- Ruthie. - What?
过来看孩子  他们在瞎胡闹
Come take care of this, they're running riot.
-我做饭呢  你看着  -我谈生意呢
- I'm cooking, you do it. - I'm in a business meeting.
你还有多余的枪吗
You wouldn't have an extra gun, would you?
算了
Forget it.
你昨晚去哪了
Where you was last night?
去哪了  竟然把我的东西都扔出去了
Where were you? Throwing all my stuff out there.
你竟然把我的东西都扔在大街上  利蒂希娅
You're throwing my stuff out here on the street, Letitia?
你这个骗子  我知道你在干什么
You lyin'. I know what you're doing.
我没叫你来
I ain't ask you to come around.
发生什么事了  詹姆斯小姐
What's going on here, Miss James?
跟你没关系
None of your damn business.
-他打你了  -去你们的
- He beating on you? - Fuck y'all!
他是个混蛋  我要他滚
He a walled-eyed son-of-a-bitch, and I want him gone!
这是我的家  我的家
This is my house, my house.
我床上不留他
I don't need him in my bed no more.
丹尼尔·麦迪逊  从房子里出来
Daniel Madison. Step on out now. Come on.
-去你妈的  -骂人不能解决问题  快出来
- Fuck y'all. - That won't help. Come on out.
没人能命令我  你不能
I don't take no shit from nobody. Not from you.
那个老太婆也不能
And not from this old crow right here.
你不过是个擦鞋的  满嘴胡话的酒鬼
You ain't nothing but shoeshine, jabber, and Aqua Velva.
她昨晚在哪  你问她
Where was she at last night? Ask her that.
我才不要在跨年夜
I ain't sitting around watching your drunk ass
对着你这个醉鬼
all New Year's Eve.
退后  退后
Step back. Step back.
我要杀了她
I'm gonna kill her.
我现在就杀了她
I'm gonna kill her right here.
你不会那么做的
You ain't gonna do nothing like that.
别这样  丹尼尔
Now, Daniel.
我们只是在闲聊
Right now, we're just having a little chat.
你才不是警察
You ain't no kinda police.
-我有警徽  -你只是披着一身皮而已
- Badge say otherwise. - Just dress you up, blood.
你就是只拿着玩具枪  拴在绳子上的猴子
Monkey on a leash with a pop gun.
我是个有尊严的男人  而她背叛了我
I'm a proud man and she's been running out on me.
我不会容忍这种事
And I won't abide it.
她昨晚只是去了教会
She went nowhere but Zion Baptist last night.
你怎么知道
How you know that?
因为克拉拉和我在那遇到她了
'Cause Clara and I saw her there.
我们一起喝了点酒  一起跨了年
We all had punch, and saw the year out.
我说的对吗  詹姆斯女士
Ain't that so, Miss James?
所以不如把枪交给我吧
So why don't you just give me that?
这是新开始的一天  哪里糟到要杀人了
Day for fresh starts. Ain't nothing never been so bad.
怎么样
What you say?
给我吧
Come on.
好了
All right.
请帮我拿一下
If you don't mind, just for one moment.
再也不要拿枪指着警察
Don't you ever pull a gun on a police officer.
-混蛋  -德雷克警官  德雷克警官
- Motherfucker. - Officer Drake. Officer Drake.
别过来  不然把你也抓起来
Step on back now unless you want some too.
你要干什么
The hell you playing at?
德雷克警官  有些东西你得看一下
Officer Drake, there's something you gotta see.
往里走  206号房
Straight on. Two-oh-six.
我不能再过去了
This is as far as I go.
我已经进去过一次  不想再进去了
I've been in there once, I don't need to go in again.
把人从教堂里带出来  天啊
Pulling him out of church, for God's sake.
做事要讲程序  警探  你得通知他的律师
There's a process, Detective. You're to notify his counsel.
-你不是来了吗  -事先通知
- Well, you're here, aren't you? - Notify beforehand.
还有你说的嫌疑人在哪
And where's this line-up you promised?
没关系  乔纳森先生  我想帮忙
It's okay, Mr. Jonathan, I wanna help.
他想帮忙
He wants to help.
所以  这个箱子是你的吗
So, what do you think?
看起来确实很像我的那个
It sure looks like my suitcase.
只是一点  这是什么
I'd be certain except-- What's this here?
弹孔
It's a bullet hole.
你怎么找到这个箱子的  警探
And how did this suitcase come to be in your possession, Detective?
牛顿分局的人在一间废弃的公寓里发现的
Newton Division found it in an abandoned apartment.
一起发现的还有几具尸体
Along with a couple of stiffs.
EB·乔纳森  你这个老家伙
E.B. Jonathan, you old so-and-so.
你一定是马修·多德森
You must be Matthew Dodson.
梅纳德·巴恩斯  抱歉我来晚了
Maynard Barnes. Sorry I'm late.
巴恩斯先生是地方检查官
Mr. Barnes is the District Attorney.
虽然我不知道他为什么来这
Though I'm not sure why he's here.
应该跟你来这里的理由相同  EB
Similar interests, I assume, E.B.
别让我打断你们  继续吧
But let me not interrupt.
我们在说中央大街的那几具尸体
We were talking about the Central Avenue stiffs.
对  我们认为这几个看来遭人灭口的人
Yes, well, we believe these men, murder victims it seems,
他们与你儿子被绑架
were involved in the kidnapping
并被撕票的事有关
and subsequent death of your son.
-这是好消息  是吗  -有关
- That-- that's good, right? - Involved?
你有枪吗  多德森先生
You have a gun, Mr. Dodson?
-什么  -当然有
- What? - Yeah, sure.
什么枪
What kinda gun?
先等等  马修
Hold on, Matthew.
我们这是在干什么  梅纳德
What exactly are we doing here, Maynard?
查理被绑架的那晚你在哪  多德森先生
Where were you the night Charlie was taken, Mr. Dodson?
我说过了
I told you guys.
我当时在店里算账
I was at the store, totaling the receipts.
行了  我们走
All right, let's go.
坐下  EB
Sit down, E.B.
因为你当时没在工作  对不对
Because you weren't working, were you?
把我们骗来这里
Bring us down here under false pretenses
就为了打我们个措手不及
for some goddamn ambush?
-我们不干了  -给我坐下  老爷子
- This is over. - Sit the fuck down, gramps.
别用这种口气对我说话
Don't you speak to me like that.
一名巡警在那晚经过了你的杂货店两次
A patrol officer stopped by your grocery twice that night
检查一扇开着的门顶窗
to check on an open transom window.
而你都不在店里
And you weren't there!
你其实在家  马修
You were at home, Matthew.
在你儿子被带走的当晚  你在家
At home, the night your son was taken.
我们有目击证人
We have an eyewitness.
他由律师代表
This man is represented by counsel.
-他对此无可奉告...  -看到他从后门进去
- He has nothing to say... - Saw him go in the back door.
-我真不在  -看到他...
- I wasn't there! - Saw him come out...
-我对天发誓  一分钟后出来
- I swear to God! - ...A minute later
手里抱着东西
with something in his arms.
能卖钱的东西
Something he could turn into money.
一笔能快速偿还债务的赃款
A quick score to settle his debts,
因为你欠了一屁股的债  不是吗  马修
because you owe all over town, don't you, Matthew?
我要提起正式诉讼
I'm gonna lodge a formal complaint.
你们对他如此纠缠不休...
Badgering this man with nothing but--
我有他的作案动机和时机
I got motive. I got opportunity.
是吗  你有...
Yeah, you have...
梅纳德  你就只有一桶屎
Maynard, you have entirely a bucket of eels.
是吗
Really?
你打算告诉陪审团这个人绑架了自己的儿子
You're gonna tell a jury that this man kidnapped his son
就因为他负债累累
because he had debts?
所以他计划向自己敲诈一笔
And that his plan was to extort money,
他根本拿不出手的钱
which he clearly didn't have, from himself?
那请你的便
Please, be my guest.
我准备花两块钱理个发
I'm gonna get a two-dollar haircut
好让我能帅气地出现在报纸上笑掉大牙
so that I look good in the papers laughing my ass off.
我们走  马修  你们真可耻
Come on, Matthew. Shame on all of you.
这其实也是我们想不通的一点
That was the one thing we couldn't quite figure.
为何要绑架一个杂货店主的小孩
Why pull a snatch job on a grocer's kid?
还勒索十万  这么大数目
And a hundred thousand? Why so steep?
没道理啊
Makes no sense.
除非那人知道他身上有钱
Unless he knew he had the money
或者知道他能弄到这笔钱
or knew that he could get the money.
比如说从他有钱的爸爸那儿
Like from his rich father, perhaps.
不过谁又会知道这种事呢
But who'd know a thing like that?
毕竟这是个严守的秘密
I mean, such a well-kept secret.
你要猜猜看吗  多德森先生
Wanna take a guess, Mr. Dodson?
还是说应该叫你  巴格利先生
Or should we call you Mr. Baggerly?
巴格利
Baggerly?
赫尔曼是你父亲
Herman is your father?
你被捕了  硬汉
You're under arrest, tough guy.
新年快乐
Happy New Year.
理发的事就先别想了  EB
Might wanna hold off on that haircut, E.B.
-等等  -让我来
- Now wait a minute. - Here, let me get that.
巴恩斯  你不能...
Barnes, you're not getting...
你...
You're...
-巴恩斯  这样不对...  -马修
- Barnes, this isn't-- - Matthew?
-这样不对  艾米莉  -马修
- This is not the way. Emily. - Matthew?
-这是怎么回事  -好了  冷静下
- What is going on here? - All right. Just calm down.
-马修  -我必须得告诉你
- Matthew? - I have to tell you
-现在发生的事  -马修
- what's happened there... -  Matthew?
-怎么了  马修  -我们都始料未及
- What's-- Matthew. - it's nothing we didn't expect.
马修  马修
Matthew! Matthew!
-他招供了吗  -是什么罪名
- He confessed? - What's the charge?
你要起诉多德森吗
You're nailing Dodson for it?
他是凶手吗
He's going down for it?
马修·多德森因密谋绑架罪被逮捕
Matthew Dodson is being held on conspiracy kidnapping charges,
这也再次证明  在我的管理下
proving once again that, under my watch,
我们能快速镇压犯罪活动
criminal activities will be quickly put down
也能严格执法
and the laws energetically enforced
以造福众生  拍吧
to the benefit of all. Take it.
就这样
That's it.
多德森  多德森先生
Dodson. Mr. Dodson.
密苏里州的一个女人
A woman in Missouri.
她骗了我
She lied to me.
当然是我的错  但我也是被骗了
My fault certainly, but I was lied to.
我那时还不是现在这样
I was a different man then.
那么马修是你儿子吗
So Matthew is your son?
他几年前找到我
He found me a few years ago.
我们算是做了个安排
We made kind of an arrangement.
他信奉上帝
He would give himself to the Lord,
我会为他提供在这安居乐业
I would provide the means to resettle him here
所需的一切
and start a business.
就算有烦恼  他也是个敬畏主的孩子了
He's a God-fearing boy now. Not without his troubles.
比如他现在面临的绑架指控这种烦恼吗
Like the kidnapping charge he's up against?
他绝不会参与那样的事
He would never get involved with anything like that.
绝不吗  他跟警察说谎很熟练
Never? He sure lied to the cops like a pro.
因为他在案发当晚
Because he was engaged in illegal gambling
参与了非法赌博
on the night in question.
在那个情况下  我能理解他的犹豫
Given the circumstances, I can understand his hesitation.
他们现在有个目击证人看到他在家
They now have a witness who saw him at home.
你就要去找一个证人证明他在赌博
And you're gonna find one that saw him rolling dice.
我保证  梅森先生
I assure you, Mr. Mason,
我儿子不会做害人的事
my son is incapable of harming anyone,
更别说害我孙子了
let alone my grandson.
你听听他说的
Listen to this guy.
突然间就变成"我儿子""我孙子"
Now, suddenly, it's "my son," "my grandson."
上周你还分不清他
Last week, you didn't know Matthew
-和园丁  -冷静点  小子
- from the fucking gardener. - Take it down a peg, boy-o.
要是骗我们  你就浪费钱了  巴格利先生
You waste your money, Mr. Baggerly, if you lie to us.
我没撒谎  我也不会撒谎
I did not lie. I do not lie.
我告诉了你们该知道的信息
I told you what you needed to know.
你告诉我们  他是你教会的成员
You told us he was one of your fellow parishioners in your church,
你没说你赶火车的时候还上了他妈
not that you knocked up his mother in between train whistles.
我听说你是个功勋卓著的军人
And I was told that you were a decorated serviceman.
但其实你收到蓝票  被开除军籍
But actually you were discharged with a blue ticket.
蓝票是给那些惹麻烦的军人的
A blue ticket is reserved for undesirable servicemen.
同性恋和黑人
Homosexuals and Negroes.
你不是黑人吧
You're not Negro, are you?
我有四分之一威尔士血统  只碰过一个男人
No, I'm a quarter Welsh and queer only once.
我听说他们叫你
I heard they called you
"蒙福贡的屠夫"
the "Butcher of Montfaucon."
被送上了军事法庭
Brought before a military tribunal.
我所闻可还准确  梅森先生
Did I hear wrong, Mr. Mason?
我们都只告诉别人
We tell one another what we need to tell
该说的事  不是吗
one another, do we not?
孩子  你要不
Son, why don't you get--
我再去趟多德森家
I'm gonna double back to the Dodsons'.
会会这个突然想起来
Check out this witness that suddenly remembers
在小巷见过马修的目击证人
seeing Matthew in the alley.
我跟他们的目击者聊了
So I spoke to the guy, their witness,
一个基特先生  你认识吗
a Mr. Kitt. You know him?
不认识  也说不定
No, I-- Maybe.
就是你马路对面的一个邻居
One of your neighbors just across the way there.
我不怎么跟人交往
I don't socialize much.
没事
No matter.
他说看见马修
He said he saw Matthew
在查理被带走时
go down the side of the house
走过了房子一侧
when Charlie was taken.
更糟糕的是
Which sounds worse than it is,
基特先生的原话是他看见"一个男人"
'cause Mr. Kitt originally told the police he saw "a man."
在警方第三次威逼下  改口"看见马修"
Turned into "saw Matthew" third time they leaned on him.
这是好事吧  他不能确定
I suppose that's good that he wasn't sure.
-你确定不是马修吗  -当然确定
- Are you sure it wasn't Matthew? - Of course I am.
问这些问题是我的工作
It's my job to ask these questions.
我只是在谈可能情景
I'm only talking about what might be possible.
你
You, um...
你听着收音机
you fell asleep in front of the fire...
在炉火前睡着了
listening to the radio.
是鲁迪·瓦利  弗莱希曼的酵母时间
It was Rudy Vallee. Fleischmann's Yeast Hour.
我努力一次不落
I try to never miss it.
当鸣鸟歌唱
When songbirds are singing
嗨哟  各位  嗨哟
Heigh-Ho, everybody Heigh-Ho
-你也喜欢鲁迪·瓦利吗  -也不是
- You like Rudy Vallee, too? - Not really.
就是那种不管你愿不愿意
Just one of those things that gets in your head,
都会不由自主记住的东西
whether you want them there or not.
你和马修之间怎么样
How are things between you and Matthew?
如果你想胡诌什么故事  梅森先生
If you wanna push stories, Mr. Mason,
出去跟记者站在一起
go on outside and stand with the reporters.
站在外面  跟他们那群人一起
Stand out there, and shout at my windows
对着我家窗户大喊大叫
with the rest of them.
马修绝不会伤害查理
Matthew would never... hurt Charlie.
艾米莉  带走你儿子的人从来没想伤害他
Emily, whoever took your son never meant to hurt him.
他们只想要钱
They just wanted money.
然后事情出了大岔子
And something went horribly wrong.
你要抽烟吗
Can I offer you a cigarette?
我更希望你别在这里抽烟
I'd prefer you not smoke in here,
如果你不介意的话
if it's all the same to you.
当然
Of course.
我们只收留了母的
We only kept the females.
如果是生了一窝的话
I mean, when we were having litters.
我们倒不会赶走公猫
Not that we pushed the toms out, mind you.
我们是正统的天主教徒
We're right Catholics.
特罗特拿了一个篮子把公猫淹死了
Mr. Trotter got a bucket and drowned 'em.
-这是人道的做法  -当然了
- It's the humane thing to do. - Of course.
自己玩去  赛迪美
Settle yourself, Sadie Mae!
查理消失的那天晚上  你看到奇怪的事情了吗
Did you see anything odd the night Charlie disappeared?
没有  抱歉
No. Sorry.
没有陌生人  陌生的车辆
No strangers? No unfamiliar cars?
只有在打电话闲聊的太太
Just the missus gabbing away on the phone.
要我说  是她丈夫太过忙于工作了
You ask me, the mister works too much.
可怜的姑娘  一整晚都在打电话
Poor girl talks on the phone all night,
只希望能有个人能聊天  有点可悲
just to have someone to talk to. Kinda sad.
你说她那天晚上在打电话
You say she was on the phone that night?
快看  她又在打电话了
Look, she's at it again.
并指导录制我们电台的问候语
And directing the recording of our radio greetings.
嗨哟  各位  嗨哟
Heigh-ho, everybody, heigh-ho!
冲
Go!
快点  跟我上
Come on, with me.
求你了  动手吧
Please, do it.
求你
Please.
求你动手
Please do it.
杀了我  求求你
Kill me. Please do it.
鲜花  讣告的内容
Flowers, obituary composition,
骨灰盒和墓碑  及碑上的铭文
casket and tombstone, the inscriptions thereon.
我们的职责就是负责每一个细节
It is our business to take on every detail
好让你和你丈夫
so that you and your husband...
好让你和你的家人
So that you and your family
可以先整理自己的悲痛
can concentrate on the grieving at hand.
我们有很多不同的骨灰盒
Now, we have a variety of caskets.
大多数是用绸缎做里衬
Most are lined in satin,
刺绣是来自一流的奥克斯纳德市女裁缝
and the embroidery is first rate from a seamstress in Oxnard.
基础款棺椁  奢华款棺椁
这些都不错  这款  这款
Well, any of these. This one. This one.
我想推荐这一款
Ah. Might I suggest this one.
红木外壳  蓝色绸缎里衬
Redwood casing, blue interior satin,
枕头上有金色叶子
gold leaf on the pillowing
-而且这款  -我饿了
- and it's available... - I'm hungry.
只有婴儿大小
...in an infant's sizing.
我自从昨天早上开始就没吃东西了
I haven't eaten since yesterday morning.
拉奇蒙特有一家不错的餐厅
You know, there's a swell diner down on Larchmont.
艾米莉小姐  不如让我来处理这些事宜
Ms. Emily, why don't you let me handle the affairs
让黛拉开我的车送你去吧
and Della can drive you down there in my car.
先生们  谢谢
Gentlemen. Thank you.
-先生们  -怎么了
- Gentlemen? - Yes.
-多德森夫人  -多德森夫人
- Mrs. Dodson? - Mrs. Dodson?
多德森夫人
Mrs. Dodson,
你丈夫被捕之后  你跟他谈话过吗
have you talked with your husband since the arrest?
你当晚在喝酒吗  你丈夫...
Were you drinking the night your husband--
你认为是你丈夫亲手杀了查理吗
Do you think your husband killed Charlie himself?
多德森夫人  是开棺葬礼
Mrs. Dodson, is it going to be an open casket
还是打算火化呢
or are you cremating the body?
晚上睡得安心吗
Sleep well at night, do ya?
不要挡我的路
Hey. Get out of my way.
真是够奇怪的  在这附近发现两具白人尸体
Odd enough, finding two dead white folks around this way.
时不时的确能发现死掉的煤炉工  茶水工
I mean, occasionally, you find a stiff coal burner, a tea head,
但大多数时候  都是被人拿刀捅死的
but that's mostly about a knife stuck in them somewhere.
子弹  这是处决
Bullets, see, that's-- that's executive murder.
再加上那手提箱
That and the suitcase.
你就把这事跟之前听到的案情联系起来了
And you connected that off the briefings?
是的  长官  还有那帽子和素描
Yes, sir. And the hat. That sketch.
报告里提到了一处血迹
Report here mentions a blood trail.
是的  长官  沿逃生梯通向楼顶
Yes, sir. Up the fire escape to the roof.
然后通向了哪里
Leading to what?
-线索断了  -断了
- Nothing. - Nothing?
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
可能是你弄错了
Could be you got that wrong.
可能血迹是从屋顶开始  指向楼下
Could be the trail starts on the roof and leads down.
是的  长官  有可能
Yes, sir. Could be.
只是  血滴
Ah. Only the, uh, the drops of blood.
血溅的尾部指向上楼方向
The tail on the splash points up those stairs.
瞧瞧这小子啊
Wow, get a load of this character.
德雷克警官是位侦探
Officer Drake here is a detective.
对吗  德雷克警官
Ain't that right, Officer Drake?
你像我和恩尼斯警长一样是侦探吗
You a detective like me and Sergeant Ennis?
不  长官  不是的
No, sir. No.
因为没有黑人侦探
'Cause there are no colored detectives.
可能德雷克警官会成为第一个
Hmm, maybe Officer Drake's gonna be the first.
我个人不赞同这种政策
I personally disagree with the policy.
我小时候就有黑人保姆
Had me a colored mammy as a young-'un.
我也乐意跟黑人警探合作
Just as soon as work with a colored detective as Ennis.
但  生活如此嘛
But, uh... such is life.
干得不错  德雷克
This is some good work, Drake.
真的不错
Real good.
莫顿指挥官
你没吃什么东西
You haven't eaten very much.
-抱歉  -没事
- Sorry. - No. It's okay.
我近来会环顾四周  感觉我忘了什么
I look around lately, thinking I forgot something.
又没人可问
But there's nobody there to ask.
EB会处理好一切的
E.B. will take care of everything.
你不用担心
Don't you worry.
不用担心
Don't worry.
我们刚去给我儿子买了棺材
We just went casket shopping for my son.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
-请保持连线  -谢谢你  接线员
- Hold for your connection, please. - Thank you, Operator.
你好  接线员  接线员
Hello, Operator? Operator?
我是接线员  请问您要接到哪里
Operator. How may I direct your call?
我妻子刚刚想
Uh, yeah. My wife was just trying to, uh,
打给她的医生
reach her doctor
但好像断线了
but, well, it seems she got cut off.
稍等  先生  我重新连线
One moment, sir. I'll try the line again.
非常感谢  女士
Thank you kindly, ma'am.
对不起  先生
I'm sorry, sir.
对方似乎无人接听
Your party doesn't seem to be answering.
无人接听吗  这很重要
No answer? Well, this is real important.
是医疗上的事情
It's a medical situation, you see.
对不起  先生
I'm sorry, sir.
你在接哪个号码
Well, what number are you trying?
西拉3-6517
Sierra 3-6517.
老天  那是我们自己的号码
Holy crow, that's our own number.
难怪无人接听  谢谢
No wonder we're not home. Thank you.
这里的咖啡不错吧
Great coffee they got here, huh?
你他妈为什么跟着我们
Why the hell are you following us?
EB想确保
Well, E.B. wanted, uh, to make sure,
外面那么多记者
you know, with all the reporters, that--
你真不会撒谎  更不会盯梢
You're a bad liar. And a lousy tail.
我没必要向你解释什么  黛拉
I don't have to explain shit to you, Della.
我在办案  我在工作
I'm-- I'm-- I'm working the case. I'm doing my job.
孩子  我送你回家吧
Hey, kid, let's get you home, okay?
我是接线员  请问您要接到哪里
Operator, how may I direct your call?
博伊尔2-3405
Uh, Boyle 2-3405.
稍等  先生
One moment, sir.
-信使交易所  -戴安娜  是我
- Messenger Exchange. - Dianne, it's me.
今天你叫出我的名字了
Oh, he knows my name today!
是的  你有反向搜索簿吗
Yes, I-- I-- Look, do you have the reverse look-up handy?
我要找一个名字和地址  西拉3-6517
I need a name and an address. Sierra 3-6517.
回来的感觉不错吧
Must feel good. To be back.
你是这里的老成员了
You look quite the stalwart around here.
我不敢这么说
I wouldn't say that.
我看了照片  听说了一些故事
I've seen the pictures, heard some stories.
很多故事
A lot of stories, actually.
可以说是创始会员
Practically an original member.
"城里最好的年轻人"之一
One of the "best young men the city contained".
那时候这座城很小  至于"最好"
Smaller city back in those days and "best..."
总是相对的
has always been a relative term.
很抱歉让你那么难堪
I'm sorry for, uh, catching you out like that.
这是个大案子  压力很大
It's a big case. Lot of pressure.
我绝无不敬之意
And there was no disrespect intended.
所以我才要求见你
That's why I asked to meet with you.
好  那你就说吧
Okay. So let's hear it already.
多德森签供认书  我就不提绞刑
Dodson signs a confession. I take hanging off the table.
我们把杀人归罪到其中一个死人头上
We pin the murder on one of the dead guys.
-干净利落  -我喜欢
- That's tidy. - I like it.
市长也喜欢  新闻记者也会喜欢的
Mayor likes it. The Newshawks are gonna love it.
你整过我一次  梅纳德  不会有下一次了
You took me once, Maynard. It won't happen again.
我很享受  这不是我常说的话
I relish, and that's not a word I throw around casually,
一想到与你对簿公堂  我就很期待
I truly relish the thought of going into court with you.
如果你是巴格利的朋友
If you are Baggerly's friend,
你应该享受救他儿子的机会
you should relish the chance to save his son's life.
马修·多德森是无辜的
Matthew Dodson is innocent.
得了吧  我有目击证人  我有
Oh, come on, I have an eyewitness, I have--
我的调查员正在调查
My investigator is currently looking
你掌握的东西是怎样少得可怜
into what little you have.
这是能判绞刑的  EB  不是什么白发老太
This is a hanging case, E.B., not some gray-hair
想把她的毛衣留给一只猫
that wants to leave her sweaters to a cat.
为你自己着想  考虑一下是否
Do yourself a favor, and consider the possibility
你可能无法驾驭这个案子
you may be out of your depth.
你想呆多久都行
Stay as long as you want.
再喝一轮吧  记我账上
Have another round. On me.
先生们
Gentlemen.
当地各界强烈抗议  马修·多德森应该被处绞刑
上帝广播集会将向小成员道别  愿我们永远不会经历他可怜母亲的悲痛
我们安排卡特市长坐哪儿
Where are we putting Mayor Carter?
在阳台下面的包厢
On the house right under the balcony lip.
不  不  不  那还不够近
Oh, no. No, no, no, no. That's not nearly close enough.
我们把他安排在...靠过道的位置
Here, we'll put him on the-- on the aisle.
我记得你安排了
I-- I believe that's where you've sat
克拉克·盖博先生坐那儿  麦基根嬷嬷
Mr. Clark Gable, Mother McKeegan.
他不是一米八多吗
Well, he's a bread loaf over six feet, isn't he?
他的确是个高个儿  嬷嬷
He is a tall man, yes, Mother.
我们不能让市长为了看清舞台
Well, we can't have the mayor leaning and preening
-歪来倒去  -按说
- trying to see the stage. - You'd have thought
如此悲痛的场合会让人避而远之  但是...
grim circumstances would have driven everyone away, but...
谁能想到我们会主持这样的活动呢
Well, who knew we were even hosting the event.
但事到如此  我们就要像
But here we are. And we should do this
以往一样主持这次活动  精益求精
as we do all things. Best and better.
布朗长老
Elder Brown,
布朗太太是否愿意让出她的位置
would Mrs. Brown be willing to part with her seat
让市长能有更清晰地看到台上的活动
to offer the mayor a clear view of the stage?
悉听尊便
Whatever accommodates.
我会保证在我们离开前往墓地前
I'll make sure she gets a moment with Mr. Gable
她会有机会和盖博先生互动
before we part to the cemetery.
或许更适合直接在墓地
Perhaps it would be wise to move the event
举办这个活动  考虑到...
directly to the cemetery, considering...
考虑到什么
Considering what?
要埋葬一位成员的孩子
A member's child is being laid to rest.
但...同时他也被起诉谋杀
But... one is also being charged with murder.
绑架  不是谋杀
Kidnapping. Not murder.
况且警察在此事上大错特错
And the police are in serious error on that matter.
我只是在想这是否对我们教堂来说关注度太高
I merely wonder if this is a light too bright for our church.
这不是我儿子干的
My son did not do this.
如你我一样  他也是基督的儿子
He's a child of Christ's blood, just like you and me.
别因为他身世的罪孽
Do not let the sin of his birth,
以及我向你们隐瞒这件丑事
nor the fact that I kept this shame from all of you...
而产生偏见
Do not let it blind you.
哀恸的人有福
Blessed are the mourners.
这难道不是你们听过最正确的一句话吗
Isn't that the truest thing you ever heard?
嬷嬷  巴格利兄弟  明天我能对此进行演说吗
Mother, Brother Baggerly, can I speak on that tomorrow?
听上去不错  修女
That sounds lovely, Sister.
我相信这会给出席的所有人带来莫大的安慰
I'm sure that'll bring great comfort to all those in attendance.
当地各界强烈抗议  马修·多德森应该被处绞刑
正义是否会降临
卖福乐刷子的  来把好用的新刷子吧
Fuller Brush Man. Get a handy new brush
只耽误你两分钟时间
for just two minutes of your time.
外面那是你的车吗
That your car outside?
我想问你几个问题
'Cause I'd like to ask you a few questions.
我无法承受我们所做的一切  你能在胡佛街79号找到另外两个人  愿主饶恕我这个罪人
怎么了
What?
工作上的事
It's work.
巡逻指挥官说我犯了一个错误
Watch Commander say I made a mistake.
但我没犯错  但他说我犯了  所以...
'Cept I didn't make no mistake. 'Cept he says I did. So.
我得修改我的报告
I had to change my report.
-那个乔·莫顿吗  -是的
- This Joe Morton? - Yeah.
你说"乔·莫顿比一袋榔头还蠢"
You say, "Joe Morton dumber than a bag of hammers."
那是因为他的确比一袋榔头还蠢
That's 'cause he is dumber than a bag of hammers.
那你为什么要改报告
So why'd you change it?
宝贝  你觉得呢
Baby, why do you think?
离我远点  警官
Outta my face, cop.
你要喊德雷克警官  利普女士
That's Officer Drake to you, Ms. Lip.
"亲爱的乔治  雨季过去了  季节又再次更替  春天来了  暖风轻柔地吹散这个时节从海里的雾气"
"我别无所求  只有这个"  艾米莉
"下次见"  艾米莉
伙计  除非有市警局允许  禁止探视
Hey, pal. No visitors unless it's cleared downtown.
我为他们律师工作
Yeah. I work for their attorney.
我不管你为谁工作  回你车里
I don't care who you work for, you get back in the truck.
快停下
Hey, stop right there.
多德森太太
Mrs. Dodson?
-艾米莉  -感觉到了吗
- Emily? - Hey, you feel that?
-我会...  -梅森先生
- I will... - Mr. Mason?
看到了吗  她认识我
See? She knows me.
-怎么回事  -安静点
- What's going on? - Be quiet.
你弄疼我了
You're hurting me.
谁是乔治·甘农
Who's George Gannon?
-乔治  甘农  -谁是乔治·甘农
- George... Gannon? - Who's George Gannon?
-我不认识任何叫...  -别  别  别
- I don't know anyone named-- - Don't, don't, don't...
-别这么做  -他是一个教堂的朋友
- Don't do it. - He's a friend from church.
不要  不要对我撒谎
Do not-- Do not lie to me, do not lie to me.
谁是乔治
Who's George?
我俊美的乔治
"My beautiful George,
距离我们上次见面才过去三天
It's been three days since we saw each other,
但感觉就像过去了三年
but it feels more like three years..."
他是教堂那边的朋友
He's a friend from church.
带我走  乔治  去海里的某座岛屿
"Take me away, George. To some island in the ocean.
烧掉带我们到那里的小船
And set fire to the boat that got us there..."
那些信不是你的
Those aren't yours.
上帝一定希望我们在一起
"God must want us to be together,
不然我们不会有这样的感受
or we wouldn't be feeling this way.
我爱你胜过所有人  艾米莉
I love no one more than you, Emily."
-乔治在哪儿  -乔治已经死了
- Where's George? - George is dead.
不
No.
No!
不  她在说谎
No, she's lying!
我给过她全盘招供的机会  她犹豫了
I gave her a chance to come clean, she dithered.
现在她还让她丈夫为此上绞架
Now, she's letting her husband swing for it.
你从犯罪现场取证
Hey, you took evidence from a crime scene!
你可能会因此丢掉执照
You could lose your license for this!
他们不需要知道我是从哪儿找到这些的
They don't have to know where we got them.
这能让我们的委托人免罪
It gets our client off.
但却让另一位委托人上绞架
And gets another client the rope.
你到底接不接电话
Are you gonna answer that?
委托人是赫尔曼·巴格利  他掏了大钱
The client is Herman Baggerly, who's out a hundred thou,
他的妻子和合法的孩子都会因此蒙羞
whose wife and legitimate kids are gonna get humiliated.
没错  老子撒谎  儿子犯浑
Yes. A lying dad, with a bastard son,
儿媳出轨
and a daughter-in-law who's a goddamn cheat.
-圣三一  -你闭嘴
- The holy trinity. - You shut up.
-他就是个废物  -我说的吧
- He's a degenerate. - See?
他连词都用的跟我一样
He even used the word!
不  别闭嘴  跟他说说你查到了什么
No. Don't shut up. Tell him what you got.
我找到了两个自称晚上曾跟多德森一起
I tracked down two chinks say they were in that dice joint
赌博的中国佬
with Dodson on the night.
我让你去查马修的不在场证明
I told you to check out Matthew's alibi.
他光跟踪艾米莉和我就够忙的了
He was too busy following Emily and me.
对  还好我那么做了
Yeah. Good thing I did.
她跟查理的凶案没关系
She had nothing to do with Charlie's murder.
但看这些信可不是那样
Well, these letters say different.
这些信说明她出轨了  那又怎样
These letters say she had an affair. So what?
你又没有全天跟她待在一起
You didn't spend the day with her.
那女人心碎了  我有直觉  老板
The woman is broken. I got a feeling, Chief.
维斯塔路有个
There's a guy on Vista Drive
脑袋已经失去了知觉的男人
with no feeling in his fucking head...
而小查理就要在哈特-汉娜那里
and Little Charlie is about to get embalmed over
接受防腐处理了  所以不要跟我谈直觉
at Harte and Hanna. So, spare me the intuition.
我是花钱雇你接电话的吗
Do I pay you to answer the phone?
没错  是的
Yes, I do.
这里是EB·乔纳森的办公室
E.B. Jonathan's office.
请问有什么需要帮忙的
How can I help you?
警察猜对一半  是出了大岔子的勒索
Cops got it half right, it's extortion gone way wrong.
但凶手不是马修  是艾米莉
But it's not Matthew. It's Emily
和这个乔治  还有他找来的黑帮
and this guy George and the hoods he got in with.
警察教了邻居提供什么口供
The cops coached the neighbor's statement.
那晚他在巷子里看到的人是乔治·甘农
It was George Gannon he saw in the alley that night.
你不是说
I thought you said
乔治当时在打电话  分散她注意
George was on the phone, distracting her.
对  是的
Yeah. He-- he was.
-他怎么能同时做到两件事  -我也不知道
- How could he manage both? - I don't know!
也许那是中央大道的其中一个死人
Maybe he's one of the stiffs of Central Ave!
你在胡扯呢吧  小子
Pulling this outta your ass, boy-o...
这我同意
Oh, that I agree with.
还有你  在接电话的时候要说
And you, it's "E.B. Jonathan and Associates"
"EB·乔纳森和合伙人"
when you answer the phone!
已经有六年没人跟你合伙了
Haven't been associates for six years!
你们之间有些事需要处理
You people got some things to sort out.
我不会给妓院报销
I don't reimburse for whorehouses.
怎么了  我跟踪那人  总得融入进去
What? I was tailing a guy. I had to blend in!
融入...
Blend in...
听着  乔治家完全不对劲
Look, George's place was all wrong.
伪造的自杀遗书  我杀了我的同伙
A trumped-up suicide note? I kill my partners,
烧了钱  然后把自己脑袋一枪崩了
I burned the money, I blow my head off,
因为我好命苦  我很内疚吗
'cause woe is me, I have a guilty conscience?
你知道还有谁会内疚吗
You know who else has a guilty conscience?
帕西·杜蒙特  久经世故的卓越男人
Percy DuMott, sophisticated man of distinction!
你他妈的能闭嘴吗
Would you shut the fuck up?
你真让我头疼  小子
You're giving me migraines, son.
我要怎么把这纳入证据
How am I supposed to even introduce these?
我怎么拿到的
How do I get 'em?
这对马修来说就是合理怀疑
This is reasonable doubt for Matthew.
不忠不等于谋杀
Infidelity is not murder.
听着  咱们得看看手头掌握的情况
Look, we gotta look at what we got.
马修是个赌鬼  艾米莉出轨
Matthew's a gambler. Emily's a cheat.
你们有谁认为他们杀了自己的孩子吗
Either of you think they killed their kid?
-不  -我不知道
- No. - No. I don't know.
不是故意的吧
Not intentionally.
你是不是没法把这些
I don't suppose you could put these back
放回原处了
where you found them?
你让我报警了
You had me call it in.
警察应该已经到了
Cops are probably crawling already.
信留在这
The letters stay here.
等我想到最佳用法再说
We sit on them until I figure the best way to use them.
都听到了吗  等我想出办法的
Everyone hear that? Until I figure.
总得有人做领头羊  那就是我
Someone has to lead, and that's me.
我们得再买些电话
We're gonna need more phones.
要么就找代接服务
Or an answering service.
EB·乔纳森和合伙人
E.B. Jonathan and Associates.
乔纳森先生正在开会
Mr. Jonathan is in a meeting at the moment.
我可以转述给他
I can take a message.
大家准备好了
We're ready.
"哀恸的人有福了  因为他们必得安慰"
"Blessed are those who mourn, for they will be comforted."
阿门  赞美吧
Amen! Praise be!
这是我们的主耶稣基督
The words of Jesus Christ Our Lord,
在山上布道时的话语
from His Sermon on the Mount.
《圣经》的这段话还有另外一个名字
There's another name for that part of the good book,
八福
The Beatitudes.
它是如此美妙的想法
And it is a beautiful thought.
"哀恸的人有福了  因为他们必得安慰"
"Blessed are those who mourn, for they will be comforted."
阿门
Amen!
可艾米莉·多德森如何能得到安慰
But how will Emily Dodson be comforted?
这位光荣的母亲  孕育了孩子
This glorious mother, who birthed the child,
为孩子沐浴
who bathed the child,
将身体中的养分给与孩子
who fed the child from her body,
兄弟姐妹们  我们应该怎么做
how do we, Brothers and Sisters,
才能给她慰藉
provide comfort for her...
当那个孩子  查理·多德森
When the child, Charlie Dodson,
就躺在你在我面前看到的这个盒子里
lies in this very box you see before me?
我不清楚我们是否能做到
I don't know if we can.
不要误会我的意思  艾米莉
Do not misunderstand me, Emily.
你的人生不会再有
You will not know another friendless day
没有朋友的日子
for the rest of your life,
上帝作证
and God as my witness,
若我们辜负了你  拿让这座教堂
may this Temple crumble to its very foundations
倒塌到它的根基上
if we fail you.
没错  阿门
Yeah! Amen!
我面前有许多新面孔
I see new faces down in the front.
男人们
Men.
我们城市里最有权力的人们
The most powerful men in our city.
他们得到了我们慈爱之家最好的座位
Given the best seats in our loving home.
就像我不能确定我们是否能为
And just as I can't be sure that we can offer comfort
这位哀伤的母亲能提供安慰
to the mother in mourning,
我也不能确定我是否会再次见到你们
I can't be sure I'll ever see you men under our roof again.
所以让我直接对你们说话
So let me address you directly.
魔鬼将查理·多德森放入这个盒子中
The Devil put Charlie Dodson in this box.
没错
Yes!
他从地狱一跃而起
He flew up from hell,
大步走上街道
walked to our streets,
将暴虐的手放在了孩子的头上
and laid his violent hand on this child's head.
未来的日子也有八福
Beatitudes for the day at hand.
上帝保佑警察
Blessed be the police
警察收集证据对抗这个魔鬼
who will gather evidence against the Devil.
对
Yes!
上帝保佑律师
Blessed be the attorneys
律师会控告这个魔鬼
who will prosecute the Devil.
阿门
Amen!
上帝保佑陪审团  他们将给魔鬼定罪
Blessed be the jury who will convict the Devil.
上帝保佑法官  他会给魔鬼审判
Blessed be the judge who will sentence the Devil.
对
Yes!
上帝保佑侩子手  他将拧断魔鬼的脖子
Blessed be the hangman who will snap this Devil's neck.
上帝保佑掘墓人
Blessed be the gravediggers
将魔鬼埋葬  永世不得超生
who will bury the Devila thousand feet deep,
上帝保佑虫子  啖其肉  饮其血
and blessed be the worms who will eat this Devil's flesh
魔鬼从此灰飞烟灭
and disappear it from the earth.
这就是主的功勋
This is the work of the Lord.
这是为了小查理·多德森
You do this work for little Charlie Dodson.
*上帝在光明中*
*God Only Wise*
*永生的神*
*In light inaccessible*
*凡人却见不到*
*Hid from our eyes*
*天佑...*
*Most blessed...*
刚刚是在搞什么
What was that?
*全知全能的*
*Almighty, victorious*
*爱和美*
*Of goodness and love*
*赋予你的每个子民*
*To all life Thou givest*
*赋予伟大和渺小*
*To both great and small*
*赋予你的每个生命*
*In all life Thou livest*
*真谛的意义*
*The true life of all*
*我们像繁茂的树叶*
*We blossom and flourish*
*盛开在世界上*
*As leaves on the tree*
*到了冬天便会消亡*
*And wither and perish*
*但是却改变不了你*
*But naught changeth Thee*
让一下  警官  放开...
Excuse me, officers. Let go of...
艾米莉·多德森  你因涉嫌
Emily Dodson, you're under arrest
阴谋绑架查理·多德森而被捕了
for the conspiracy kidnapping of Charlie Dodson.
-不  -请跟我来  女士
- No. - Come with us, ma'am.
不  放开她
No. Let go of her!
-不不不  -放开她
- No. No. No. - Get your hands off her.
救我  救我  救我
Help me! Help me! Help me!
查理
Charlie!
不  求求你们不要
Please. Please don't do this!
求求你们不要
Please don't do this!
-查理  -回来
- Charlie! - Get back.
查理
Charlie!
查理  不要这样
Charlie! Please don't do this.
求你们了
Please.
查理
Charlie!
求你们不要  不要
Please, don't do this! Please, don't!
我的宝贝
My baby.
你在上帝身边
你是被救赎的
红顶
安全火柴
一杯咖啡
One coffee,
一杯冷茶
one cold tea.
那是正确的决定  孩子  相信我
It was the right call, son. Believe me.
明天午餐之前就能让马修出来
We'll get Matthew out before lunchtime tomorrow.
巴格利能高兴  我们也能继续战斗
Baggerly stays happy. We stay in the fight.
不忠不是谋杀...
Infidelity is not murder...
什么
How's that?
我还在想黛拉说的这句话
It's what Della said. It's still in my head.
他们已经抓错了人
They already arrested the wrong guy.
现在他们觉得一个教堂唱诗班的主妇
Now they're stuck with a church choir housewife
是密尔沃基绑架集团主使吗
part of a kidnapping ring out of Milwaukee?
就算真是她干的  也别想能说服人
Can't see that holding, even if she did do it.
他觉得我已经是他的囊中之物了
He thinks I'm last night's eggs.
他觉得他胜券在握了  你瞧好了
Thinks he's playing me. You watch.
我们能轻松地把他扳倒
We're gonna run him over like a streetcar.
他们应该等她看到孩子下葬后再抓她
They shoulda let her see the kid get buried.
他们原本是这么说的
Oh, they said they would.
但现在谁说的话还能信呢
But who tells the truth anymore?
我不喜欢这样
I don't like it here.
我们总要为更伟大的事业
We do what we don't like
做我们不喜欢做的事
when there's a greater good to be served.
你应该最清楚这一点
You more than anyone should know that.
你知道这座城市里有多少种不同的线吗
You know how many different types of thread there are in the city?
你会查清楚的  小子
You'll find it, boy-o.
这不就是你最擅长的事吗
That's the kind of thing you're good at.
职介所
*来看看这个人*
*Come and see a man*
*诉说着我做过的一切*
*Who told me All that I had done*
*这不就是被称为耶稣的信使吗*
*Is this not the messenger Which is called Christ*?
*他来接受人们的敬仰*
*He came to draw Men unto Him*
*将他送上圣坛*
*Oh lift Him up that's all*
*遵从他的圣言*
*Lift Him up in His word*
*只要你宣传耶稣的名字*
*If you'll tell the Name Of Jesus everywhere*
*只要你不管去哪里*
*If you'll keep His Name a ringing*
*都记得他的名字*
*Everywhere that you go*
*人们都会敬仰他*
*He will draw men unto Him*
毒气  毒气
Gas! Gas! Gas! Gas!
回我们那边去
Get back to our side!
你在干什么  快点
What the fuck are you doing? Now!
-上尉  -原谅我
- Captain... - Forgive me.
*只有上帝的恩赐*
*...Only knew the gift of God*
*我来接受人们的敬仰*
*I came to draw men unto me*
*将他送上圣坛*
*Oh lift Him up, that is all*
*遵从他的圣言*
*Lift Him up in His word*
*只要你宣传耶稣的名字*
*If you'll tell the Name Of Jesus everywhere*
*只要你不管去哪里*
*If you'll keep His Name A ringing*
*都记得他的名字*
*Everywhere that you go*
*人们都会敬仰他*
*He will draw men unto Him*
*将他送上圣坛*
*Oh lift Him up that's all*
*遵从他的圣言*
*Lift Him up in His word*